[
    {
        "question": "What US city is associated with Alcatraz?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find the infamous Alcatraz?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what country did the US buy the Virgin Islands?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "What links Catalonia, Andalusia, Cantabria, Galicia?",
        "answer": "They are regions of Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what Australian state would you find Fremantle?",
        "answer": "Western Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the major port town Fremantle?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What geographical boundary was first surveyed in 1763 by Charles and Jeremiah?",
        "answer": "The Mason-Dixon Line"
    },
    {
        "question": "As what is `South West Township` known in South Africa?",
        "answer": "Soweto"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Vanern is the largest lake in which country?",
        "answer": "Sweden"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state flag features the United Kingdom`s national flag in its design?",
        "answer": "Hawaii -- Officially adopted by the state in 1845, it chose to honor most powerful countries the time \u2014 the U.S. and the U.K."
    },
    {
        "question": "What plant on the Connecticut state flag is used to represent the state`s first English settlers?",
        "answer": "Grapevine -- Grapes represent peace and good luck, while the vines they grow on were considered a symbol of friendship."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Mozambique?",
        "answer": "Maputo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which African coast is Mozambique located on?",
        "answer": "East"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean does Mozambique has water access to?",
        "answer": "Indian"
    },
    {
        "question": "What island country is located east of Mozambique?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Madagascar?",
        "answer": "Antananarivo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What separates Madagascar from Mozambique?",
        "answer": "Mozambique Channel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was known as British Honduras prior to 1973?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "question": "Armagnac is a brandy originating from which area of France?",
        "answer": "Gascony"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ouagadougou is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Burkina Faso"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ouagadougou is the capital of which African country?",
        "answer": "Burkina Faso"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is Tasmania named after?",
        "answer": "Abel Tasman"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Salvador Dali museum located?",
        "answer": "St. Petersburg, Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is home to the spring festival called `Holi`?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city are the Petronas Towers located?",
        "answer": "Kuala Lumpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which direction on a map do lines of latitude go?",
        "answer": "East to west"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river runs through Rome?",
        "answer": "Tiber"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country was the Terracotta Army sealed underground?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first person to reach the North Pole in 1909?",
        "answer": "Robert Peary"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the lowest elevation in the US?",
        "answer": "Death Valley"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Isle Royale National Park?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Pine Tree State`?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name for the monetary unit used in Thailand?",
        "answer": "Thai Bhat"
    },
    {
        "question": "In California, you can`t legally buy a mousetrap without having what?",
        "answer": "Hunting license"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Texas, it`s illegal to swear in front of what?",
        "answer": "A corpse"
    },
    {
        "question": "Georgia, it`s illegal to eat what with a fork?",
        "answer": "Fried chicken"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has an official state cookie called biscochito?",
        "answer": "New Mexico -- Brought to the region by 16th-century Spanish colonists, it is a shortbread cookie flavored with cinnamon and anise."
    },
    {
        "question": "Chicago is located on the shore of what lake?",
        "answer": "Lake Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the Hopi Indian Reservation?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does `Honolulu` translate to in English?",
        "answer": "Sheltered harbor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country`s days include Fire day, Water day and Wood day?",
        "answer": "Japan`s"
    },
    {
        "question": "Arlanda airport serves which European city?",
        "answer": "Stockholm"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is so efficient that less than one percent of household waste ends up in landfills?",
        "answer": "Sweden -- About 49% of household waste is recycled, and 50% is burned in power plants to repurpose into energy to heat homes and power cars."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the highest and longest mountain range located entirely in Europe?",
        "answer": "The Alps -- The Alps span nearly 750 miles across eight countries in central and southern Europe, with Mont Blanc being the tallest mountain in both the Alps and Europe."
    },
    {
        "question": "Mount Sunflower is what US state`s highest point?",
        "answer": "Kansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What African country calls itself the `Land of a Thousand Hills`?",
        "answer": "Rwanda"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Danish peninsula lent its name to the largest naval battle of World War I?",
        "answer": "Jutland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What London square is home to Nelson`s Column?",
        "answer": "Trafalgar Square"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which island of Japan is just 26 miles form Russia at its closest point?",
        "answer": "Hokkaido"
    },
    {
        "question": "What legendary Arizona gold mine is named in honor of prospector Jacob Waltz?",
        "answer": "The Lost Dutchman mine"
    }
]